# **Shane Bauer**

Baltimore, MD, United States 443-621-6082 <u>shane@shanebauer.com</u> https://www.shanebauer.com

I am an experienced, passionate software developer. I develop, architect and ship clean, scalable solutions. I enjoy learning new technologies and am constantly working to improve my craft. In addition, I enjoy leading and mentoring other developers. I love what I do.

#### **Technical Skills**

Likes:

asp.net-mvc c# ruby python sql-server mongodb teamcity git asp.net-core jquery go reactjs vue.js

# Experience

#### Sr. Architect - Cie Digital Labs

May 2015 → Current

asp.net-mvc, sql-server, c#, mongodb, api, sdk, jira, teamcity, octopus-deploy, azure, amazon-web-services, asp.net-core, javascript, node.js

- Architect and lead developer on several ASP.NET projects for multiple clients, including Pilot Flying J, Pioneer,
   Nitto Tire, Style Haul, ASAP Tire and Tire Rack.
- Mentored and lead multiple teams, usually consisting of 2-6 developers
- Conducted code reviews and provided feedback for all project work
- Created and implemented automated build process standards using cloud-based infrastructure in AWS and Azure.
- Implemented team standards and best practices for project teams.
- Developed .NET Core CI and automated deployment standards
- · Implemented several .NET Core 2.0 apps for two clients.
- Implemented local integration tests for API work as well as automated Postman tests for external endpoint testing.
- Provided feedback and architecture guidelines for clients implementing REST-like APIs.

# Consultant - Independent Consultant

*Apr* 2010 → *Nov* 2017

asp.net, asp.net-mvc, c#, php, go, ruby, sql-server, mongodb, mysql, laravel, api, angularjs, asp.net-core, linode, digital-ocean, automated-deploy, centos, node.js, express

 Architected and developed multiple applications for a variety of clients, including MLB Trade Rumors, Hangout Ventures, Baltimore Sports and Life, Acton Mobile and Nitto Tire.

## Sr. Software Developer - Acton Mobile

Jun 2013 → May 2015

 $asp.net-mvc,\ c\#,\ and roid,\ java,\ sql-server,\ team city,\ continuous-integration,\ dynamics-crm,\ dynamics-nav$ 

- Architected and developed native mobile app on Android to track and maintain company assets and logistical data.
- Architected and developed APIs for mobile application.
- Created integrations for MS Dynamics Nav and MS Dynamics CRM for all custom applications.
- Implemented team standards and best practices for new development team.

#### Sr. Software Engineer - JBS

Jul 2012 → Jun 2013

asp.net, asp.net-mvc, c#, mongodb, sql, sql-server, ruby, ruby-on-rails, amazon-web-services, amazon-s3, amazon-ec2, amazon-elb, cruisecontrol.net

- Developed features for large scale eCommerce system for internet retailer using C#, ASP.NET MVC and SQL Server
- One of two lead developers on a multi-tenanted eCommerce SaaS implementation. At release, the service was being utilized by Guitar Center, Robbins Brothers and Music & Arts. The application uses ASP.NET MVC 4, C#, MongoDB and Memcached.
- Maintained and customized a web-based project management portal written in Ruby on Rails.

### Application Dev Programming Manager – Eastern Savings Bank

asp.net-mvc, c#, nhibernate, sql-server, iis, security, continuous-integration, cruisecontrol.net

- Developed several internal and external web applications, utilizing recognized best practices.
- Mentored and trained group of developers in .NET, using C# and ASP.NET.
- Developed standards for all .NET applications.
- · Acted as a mentor or lead for all projects.
- · Implemented CI process
- Implemented auto-deployment standards based on audit requirements for financial institutions

**Sr. Systems Developer** – MEDEX Global Group, Inc (United Healthcare) asp.net, sql-server, iis, e-commerce, continuous-integration, cruisecontrol.net

*Apr* 2006 → Aug 2007

Nov 2007  $\rightarrow$  Jul 2012

- Redeveloped ColdFusion corporate and ecommerce websites in ASP.NET to utilize a streamlined checkout process. Project resulted in a 30% increase in sales.
- Automated processing of insurance identification cards using C# and Windows Service technology.
- Developed a web-based online enrollment application using ASP.NET, C#, Ajax, MBUnit and n-layer design techniques.
- Designed and Developed standard company library used to handle a variety of tasks, included exception management.
- Architected and developed an API to access an existing CRM solution.
- Implemented software development standards.
- Implemented and maintained CruiseControl.NET for continuous integration of web projects, libraries and Windows
  applications.
- · Developed NAnt and MSBuild scripts for every project.
- Implemented Subversion version control system to replace Visual SourceSafe.

**Software Developer** – Stanley Black & Decker asp.net, vb.net, c#, sql-server

Jun 2001 → Apr 2006

- Developed Windows-based and Web-based applications utilizing .NET and classic ASP.
- Developed multiple scalable, n-layer applications for BlackAndDecker.com and DeWALT.com.
- Developed and supported over 30 applications and websites spanning various parts of the business.

BS in Computer Information Systems – Strayer University

 $2002 \rightarrow 2005$ 

# Certifications

**Education** 

 $\textbf{MCSA - Web Apps} - \text{https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/learning/mcsa-web-applications-certification.aspx} \ \textit{May 2017} \rightarrow \textit{Current} \ \text{asp.net-mvc, c\#, javascript, jquery, security, azure, css, html5}$